手续办得还顺利吗
Hey, so did everything go okay with the annulment?
没问题  都办好了
Oh, yeah, no problems. It's all taken care of.
罗斯  谢谢你
Ross, thank you.
你们要不要一起去看个电影
Hey, do you guys wanna go see a movie?
好啊
Yeah, why not?
-我去穿毛衣  -好
- Okay, umm, I'm gonna get my sweater. - Okay.
想不想听一件奇怪的事
You uh, you wanna hear something weird?
当然
Always.
我没去办注销
l didn't get the annulment.
什么
What?
我们还是夫妻
We're still married.
不要告诉瑞秋  待会见
Don't tell Rachel. See you later.
你有口香糖吗
Do you have any gum?
等等  等等
Wait! Wait! Hi! Listen,
罗斯  可以跟你谈一下吗
Ross, can l just  talk to you for just a second?
菲比  但是电影快开演了
Oh but Phoebe, we're gonna be late for the movie.
那里有计程车  计程车
There's a cab. Taxi!
真好
That's great.
来得正好  是吧  上车吧
What timing! My God, huh? There you go.
是,  但我们只是要走着去
Yeah, we're, we're actually just gonna walk '
电影院就在安洁丽大街
cause it's right up there at the Angelica.
安洁丽大街  开车
The Angelika! Go! Go!
你没去注销
You didn't get the annulment?!
我知道
l know.
罗斯
Ross?!
我尽力了
Well, I tried!
但我一到我律师办公室  脑海中就传来
but when l got to my lawyer's office, all l heard was:
"离婚三次  离婚三次"
"Three divorces! Three divorces!"
我只是不希望我墓志铭会是
Look, I just don't want my tombstone to read
"罗斯盖勒  离婚三次"
"Ross Geller: Three Divorces."
担心什么啊
Don't worry about that.
你的墓志铭你做主
Your tombstone  can say whatever you want.
你可以刻  "罗斯·盖勒  婚姻高手"
lt can say,  "Ross Geller: Good at Marriage."
我的会刻
You know? Mine's gonna say,
"菲比·布非  活埋在此"
"Phoebe Buffay: Buried Alive."
反正我不能再有另外一次失败的婚姻
All l know is, l can't have another failed marriage.
所以呢  你要娶一个
So okay what? You're gonna be married to a girl
不知情的女生当老婆吗
who doesn't even know about it?!
是女人  抱歉
Woman. Sorry.
我还没想好要怎么做
Okay, so l don't have it all  worked out quite yet.
拜托你先别告诉瑞秋
Just don't...just don't say anything to Rachel.
瑞秋是我最要好的朋友之一
Rachel is one of my closest friends.
不过当唯一知情的人
Although, being the only one who knows anything about this
感觉不赖  好吧
does makes me feel special. Okay!
停车  菲比
Okay, stop, stop! Phoebe?
瑞秋
Hey, Rach!
你搞什么啊
What was that?
抱歉  出了点小差错
Sorry. Mix-up.
电影好看吗
How was the movie?
我还没看呢
l haven't seen it yet.
那就要快了  安洁丽大街  开车
Then you'd better hurry.  The Angelica! Go! Go!
不要啊
No!
等我们同居  我可以买台泡泡糖机吗
When we move in together, can l get a gumball machine?
当然可以  乔伊不让你买吗
Of course. Joey wouldn't let you have one?
不让  跟甜食有关  他就管很严
No, when it comes to sweets,  he's surprisingly strict.
想好怎么跟他说你要搬出来了吗
Hey, have you figured out a way to tell him you're moving out?
还没  我试着要说好几次了
No, no, I keep trying, y'know?
结果我只说得出"乔伊  我得..."
And I can get out, "Joey, I have to…"
然后我就不敢说了  结果就变成
Then l lose my nerve and l finish  with,
"去上厕所"
"--go to the bathroom."
他可能以为我有病
He may think l'm sick.
我也真得告诉瑞秋这事情了
Y'know, I really have to tell Rachel, but I
早死早超生
We just gotta get it over with.
下次见到他们  我们就说
Y'know, the next time we see them we're just gonna tell them.
行吧  就这么决定
Okay? That's it.
这么快就开始了吗
Oh, so that's this is gonna work now?
你以后要常常指使我吗
You're just gonna order me around all the time?
-差不多  -好吧
- Pretty much.  - All right.
莫妮卡
Hey Monica!
-你有没有好一点  -有
-Hey, man, you feeling better? - Yeah.
乔伊  我们有事要说
Joey, we got something to tell you.
天哪
Oh, my God!
你怀孕了
You're pregnant!
不是
No!
-没有吧  -没
- No? - No.
不是
No.
乔伊  是这样的
Look, Joe, here's the thing.
莫妮卡和我决定在这里同居
Monica and l have decided  to live together, here. So...
所以我会搬出来
l'm gonna be moving out, man.
我真替你们高兴  恭喜  回见
l'm really happy for you guys. Congratulations. See you later.
等等  乔伊  你还好吗
Wait! Joey! Joey! Are you okay?!
很好  我得走了  我有戏要演
Yeah. l gotta go. l've got an acting job.
你们会信才怪
Like you'd believe that.
讨厌啦
This sucks!
我只是要搬到对门  我保证
Look, I-I'm just gonna be right across the hall and I promise you,
莫妮卡和我一分手  我就搬回去跟你住
the minute Monica and I break up I'm moving right back in with you!
好  这样吧
Okay! Look-look-look, uh,
如果你要跟他住
if you're gonna be moving in with him
我觉得我有责任揭穿他的真面目
...l feel it is my responsibility to tell you the truth about him.
他是个很烂的室友  超烂
He's a terrible roommate. Terrible.
他会忘记...
He forgets to....
他老是...
He always, he always....
我骗谁啊  他是史上最棒的室友
Who am l kidding?  He's the best roommate ever!
菲比
Pheebs.
你有看到瑞秋吗
Hey, have you seen Rachel?
-没有  怎么了  -我有个好消息
- No, why?  - l have some exciting news.
你怀孕了
You're pregnant.
不是
No!
钱德勒和我决定同居
Chandler and l are moving in together.
太好了
Oh, that's good!
不过如果你有宝宝要叫什么呢
But if you were pregnant, what would you name it?
提示  菲比
Hint, Phoebe.
怎么样
What's up?
钱德勒和我要搬到一起
Chandler and l are moving in together.
天哪
Oh, my God.
我妹妹和我的死党...
Oh, my little sister and my best friend...
搞在一起
shacking up.
太好了  太棒了
That's great. That's great.
你们俩  我也很高兴啊
Guys, l'm happy too.
好  一起来
Okay, come here.
今天真热闹
Big day, huh?
有人要同居  有人办注销
People moving in.  People getting annulled.
我要去找瑞秋了  不过...
Okay, I gotta go find Rachel but umm,
你们见到她时
if you guys see her
能不能先说些坏消息给她
could you please try to give her some really bad news
好让我的消息听起来不太坏
so mine doesn't seem so bad.
讲给瑞秋听的坏消息...
Something bad to tell Rachel.
瑞秋的坏消息  会是什么呢
Bad news for Rachel.  What could that be?
你能不能别再提了
Can you just lay off, please?
我的人生很难堪了
My life is an embarrassment.
我应该去住在别人的楼梯底下
l should  just go live under somebody's stairs.
罗斯  根本没那么严重
Ross, it's not that big a deal!
离婚三次又怎样
So you'll been divorced three times,
你还是一样能有生活  会去约会...
you'll still have a life, you'll go on dates--
才不会
No, no, l won't.
我的约会指数降到谷底
l'll be at the bottom of the dating barrel now.
比我低的只有离婚四次的人
The only guys below me will be Four-Divorce Guy...
杀人犯和...
...Murderer Guy...
地质学家
...and geologists.
罗斯  你别傻了
Ross, you're being ridiculous. Okay?
你可爱聪明又体帖
You are cute and smart and sweet.
这比离婚三次重要多了
And that is much more important than three stupid divorces.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
你交过离婚三次的男朋友吗
Have you dated anyone who's been divorced three times?
这样问不公平
That's not really fair, you know?
离过三次婚的人  通常都六十岁了
Most guys that have been divorced three times are like 60.
罗斯  只有你自己在意
Ross, nobody cares about this except you.
什么没面子都是你在想像
This embarrassment thing is all in your head.
-来  我证明给你看  -什么
- Here, l'll show you. Come here.  - What?
你们好  我的朋友罗斯即将三度离婚
Hi. Listen, My friend Ross is about to be divorced for the third time.
但你们会和他约会吧
But wouldn't you date him?
你们稍候  我去找罗斯来
And if you wait right here,  l'll go get Ross.
我还以为你是瑞秋
Thought you were Rachel.
我哪里露出破绽了
What gave me away?
我只想告诉她
I just tell her,
我得赶快告诉她
I have to get it over with.
我已经告诉罗斯和菲比  只剩她了
l told Ross and Phoebe.  She's the only one left.
所以大家都知道了
Okay, so that's it, everybody knows!
我们确定要同居了
lt's official.  We're moving in together.
不能反悔
No turning back.
你怕吗  怕吗
Are you scared? Are you?!
不怕
No.
那是我最可怕的声音  你真勇敢
That was my scariest voice.  You're very brave.
今天真惨
The worst day.
你以为自己终于受重视了
Y'know, you think you're finally making progress at work
结果老板却叫你瑞蔻儿
then your boss calls you Racquel.
我进公司前四年
Hey listen, for the first four years of my work
大家都叫我瞎勒勒
everybody called me Sha-la-lap.
-是真的  -我相信你
- Seriously.  - l believe you.
当时正在开员工大会
So, it was right in the middle of a staff meeting
当然不会有人纠正她
so of course no one else wants to correct her,
于是大家都叫我瑞蔻儿
so everyone else is calling me Raquel!
到了下班前
By the end of the day,
收发室的人已经叫成洛基了
the mailroom  guys were calling me Rocky.
我还是觉得你很好很漂亮
Well, l still think you're very, very nice and very pretty.
什么
What?
交给你了
All yours, babe.
亲爱的  坐
Sweetie, have a seat.
听我说  钱德勒和我...
Listen, Chandler and l...
要在这里同居了
...are going to live together.
住这里
Here.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
真是太棒了
That's so great!
我真替你们高兴
l'm so happy for you guys!
真的吗
Really?
你真好  还先问我
And that was so sweet of you to ask!
天啊
Oh, my god.
我们三个在一起一定会很开心
The three of us are gonna have such a good time living together!
是啊
Yes, we are.
钱德勒  你早上得注意时间
And Chandler, you're gonna have to watch those long showers
不能慢慢冲澡了
you take in the morning
因为拉蔻儿不能迟到
...because you know Racquel can't be late.
-瑞秋  -他会注意的
- Rach. - He'll work on that.
好兴奋喔
This is so exciting!
* 来敲我的门 *
* Come and knock on our door *
* 我们会在这恭候你...... *
* We'll be waiting for you... *
一旦知道内情就没那么糟了
See? Once you know the stories, it's not that bad.
第一次  老婆隐瞒性向
First marriage: Wife's hidden sexuality.
不是我的错
Not my fault.
第二次  宣誓时叫错人
Second marriage: Said the wrong name at the altar.
有一点点是我的错
A little my fault.
第三次  他们真不该让
Third marriage, well they really shouldn't allow you to get married ...
让脸上涂鸦的醉鬼结婚
...when you're that drunk  and have writing all over your face.
内华达州的错
Nevada's fault.
你们觉得怎样
Okay. So what do you think, ladies?
谁会没兴趣  谁会不想和他约会
Who wouldn't be interested? Who wouldn't want to date him?
离婚无所谓  我愿意和他约会
The divorces don't bother me. l'd date him.
但他得先恢复自由身
But not while he's still married.
那你呢  你也想吧
Okay, what about you? Wouldn't you want a date?
事实上我再也不约会了
Atually, l'm not dating at all anymore.
我发现自己
See, I figured out that I was only dating guys
老是看上对我不好的男人
that were like y'know bad for me,
所以在我决定  我解决这个前
So l decided that until I work that out...
随便啦
Good. Good. Whatever.
梅格你呢
And you, Meg?
我也不在意离婚的事
Well, l don't care about  the divorces, either.
但我不会和他约会
But l wouldn't date him.
他很明显还爱着那个瑞秋嘛
lt's just that he's obviously still in love with this Rachel girl.
什么
What?
她说"他显然还爱着这个叫瑞秋的女孩"
She said, "He's obviously still  in love with this Rachel girl."
这话太扯了
This is crazy.
没错  瑞秋是我的好朋友
l mean, yes, yes, Rachel is my good friend.
我过去确实爱过她
And l have loved her in the past...
但现在她只是我的妻子
...but now, she is just my wife.
菲比  帮我说句话好吗
Phoebe, will you help me out here?
你娶她时我也以为你爱她
Well, l thought you loved her  when you married her.
我们喝醉了
We were drunk!
喝那么多我连乔伊都会娶
l would've married Joey with that amount of alcohol.
你能娶到乔伊已经算很好了
You could do a lot worse than Joey Tribbiani!
很抱歉  但是你们错了
l'm sorry, but you guys are wrong.
我只是不想离三次婚
l just don't want  to be divorced three times.
没错  他以此为藉口
Yes, and now he's using this three divorces reason
说自己不想离婚  其实因为他爱她
because he wants to stay married to her because he loves her.
我必须说  梅格  干得好
l must say, well done. Bravo, Meg.
好
Okay! Fine! Fine!
如果你们这么想
If-if this is what you think,
那我就不管了
forget about the whole three divorce thing, okay?
我现在就去我律师办公室
l'll go to my lawyer's office right now
去办结婚注销
and get this marriage annulled, okay?
因为我一点也不爱她
She means nothing to me.
一点也不爱
Nothing!
现在是你的神经质让我发毛
Okay, now l wouldn't date you because you seem a little creepy.
我突然觉得他好有魅力
l am so attracted to him right now.
我们什么时候要跟瑞秋说实话
Okay, when are we gonna tell Rachel what is actually going to happen?
快了
Soon.
我之前说不出口
l just couldn't before.
你也看到乔伊多难过
You saw how upset Joey got.
我不忍心伤害我最好的朋友
I couldn't do that to her, she's my best friend!
乔伊也是我最好的朋友
Well, Joey's my best friend.
我不是你最好的朋友吗
l'm not your best friend?
你自己刚才说...
You just said- -
你当然是我最好的朋友
Of course you're my best friend.
但请你告诉瑞秋好吗
Would you tell Rachel though?
-好啦  至少我现在有准备了  -好
- All right. At least l'm prepared. - Okay.
好  漂亮
Oh, yes.
-不是给你的  你有不开心吗  -现在有了
- They're not for you. Are you upset?  - l am now.
你们好啊  室友
Hey, roomie.
好  再见
Okay, bye.
瑞秋
Rach,
我有重要的事要告诉你
There's something important l have to tell you.
你怀孕了吗
Are you pregnant?
没有  但我要扔掉这件衣服了
No, but l'm throwing this shirt away.
刚才有一些误会
l think there was a little misunderstanding before.
我说钱德勒和我想住到一起
When l said that Chandler and l  wanted to live together...
意思是只有我们两个人
...we meant alone together.
天啊  真好笑  我居然会误会
Oh, my God. That's funny.  l can't believe l did that.
不  亲爱的  是我不好
No, sweetie. You know what?  This is my fault.
我没说清楚
l wasn't clear.
真的很抱歉
l'm really sorry.
你可以慢慢找房子
Listen, you take as much time as you need to move out, okay?
一点也不用急
There's absolutely no rush.
好吧
Okay.
好
你不吃饼干吗
Don't you want a cookie?
好啊
Sure.
谢谢
Thanks.
需要面纸吗
Do you need a tissue?
-这是哪里的饼干  -我做的
- Where did you get these?  - l made them.
天哪  真好吃
Oh, God, they're so yummy!
以后我回家你就不在了  感觉真怪
God. lt's gonna be weird when l come home and you're not here.
没有乔伊和钱德勒家了
No more Joey and Chan's.
没有乔和钱家了
No more J and C's.
"要不要去乔伊和钱德勒家"
Want to go to Joey and Chandler's?
"不行  已经不在了"
Can't. lt's not there.
我只是搬到对面  我们还是可以跟以前一样
Look, I'm just gonna be across the hall, we can still do all the same stuff.
但以后我们就不能半夜起来
Yeah but we won't be able to like get up in the middle of the night
促膝长谈彼此的心情和未来了
and have those long talks about our feelings and the future.
我们一次也没做过啊
Not once did we do that.
我告诉瑞秋我们要自己住了
So l told Rachel that it's just gonna be the two of us.
是吗  她还好吗
Oh, yeah? Well, how'd she take it?
非常好
Really well.
令人意外的好
Surprisingly well.
没有哭  也没有生气或难过
She didn't cry.  She wasn't angry or sad.
你很不爽没把你的闺蜜弄哭吗
And you're upset because you didn't make your best friend cry?
我只求一点真情流露
All l'm asking for is a little emotion.
我们六年室友  这要求过分吗
ls that too much to ask after six years?
我和瑞秋没你们要好吗
What, are Rachel and l not as close as you guys?
没你们开心吗
l mean, did we not have as much fun?
我不值得她掉几滴泪吗
Don't l deserve a few tears?
乔伊一听到  就哭得死去活来
When we told Joey, he cried his eyes out.
我才没有哭得死去活来
l did not cry my eyes out!
但也毕竟是一个时代的结束嘛
Come on, it's like the end of an era.
再也没有乔兄和钱哥了
No more J- Man and Channy's!
我不得不问  有谁那样叫我们啊
Okay, l gotta ask, who calls us that?
你又结婚啦
You got married again?
对
Yes.
这是你两年内第二次结婚
So that's your second marriage in two years?
对  两年两次
Yes. Second in two years.
总共三次
Third, overall.
罗斯  我当了二十三年离婚律师
Ross, l have been a divorce attorney for 23 years...
没有一个客户像你这么支持我的生意
and never had I so much business from one client.
告诉我怎么回事
Why don't you tell me what happened?
基本上  瑞秋和我在赌城
Basically, Rachel and l were in Vegas,
我们喝醉了...
and we got drunk.
抱歉  她就是你上次结婚
l'm sorry, is this the same Rachel whose name you said...
叫错的那个瑞秋吗
...at the altar  in the second marriage?
对
Yes, yes, yes.
但是我并不爱她
But l do not love her.
这就好多了
That's better then.
这只是酒醉犯错  我要办注销
This was just a drunken mistake,  and l need to get it annulled.
我懂了
l see.
你考虑过接受治疗吗
Have you considered therapy?
我想今天办注销就好了
l think just the annulment for today.
-要填几份表格  -简单
- There are some forms to fill out.  - Easy.
必须有证人证明
And we'll need to have witnesses who can testify
你们当时神智不清
that you were not of uh, sound mind.
没问题
No problem.
你和瑞秋得向法官说明
And we'll need you and Rachel  to testify before a judge.
不能不找她吗
There's no way to do this without her?
我已经告诉她事情都办妥了
Because l kind of already told her it was taken care of.
你当然这么说
Of course you did.
罗斯  你和瑞秋同时在场
Look, Ross, you can't get an annulment
才能办理注销
unless you and Rachel are both there.
那找一个长得像瑞秋的人呢
What about someone  who looks like Rachel?
我会考虑接受治疗
l will think about the therapy.
我想我们应该开始分东西了
So l was thinking that maybe we should start dividing up our stuff.
好
Okay.
没必要拖拖拉拉的
No point in dragging it out.
我是说你搬走我们分开的事
Dragging out the long process of you moving out...
-我们再也不能住在一起的事  -好
- and us not living together anymore. - Okay.
-瑞秋  -嗯
- Hey, Rach? - Yeah.
这个呢  这个要归谁
What about this? Who gets this?
我不知道我想不想要  它有太多回忆
l don't know if l want it because  it might be too many memories.
-那是什么啊  -我不知道
- What the hell is that?  - l don't know.
瑞秋  大盘子呢  我要你留着大盘子
Hey, Rachel, Howa about the big plate, I want you to have the big plate.
谢谢  莫妮卡  我很喜欢这个盘子
Wow, Monica, thanks.  l love this plate.
让你想起我的物件
Something to remember me by.
你又不是快死了  我只是要搬出去
Mon, you're not dying. l'm just moving out.
我们还是会天天见面
We're gonna see each other all the time.
但这是个大转变
But still, it's a big change.
甚至像是一个时代的结束
The end of an era, you might say.
你还好吗  眼睛都没眨
Are you okay? You're not blinking.
我很好  我只是在想一个时代要结束了
l'm fine. l was thinking about how it's an end of an era.
好吧
Oh, all right.
但老实说  六年应该称不上一个时代
But y’know I gotta say, l don't think six years counts as an era.
一个时代就是一段重要的日子
An era is defined as a significant period of time.
我觉得重要  或许你不觉得重要
lt was significant for me. Maybe it wasn't significant to you!
-你是怎么了  -你才怎么了
- What is the matter with you?  - What is the matter with you?!
你为什么没有更不开心
Why aren't you more upset?
我们要分开了  难道你不难过吗
Aren't you gonna be sad that we're not living together any more?
你都不会想我吗
Aren't you gonna miss me at all?
好吧  说出来你别生气
Monica, all right.  But don't get mad at me.
只是有点难以相信嘛
lt's just a little hard to believe.
难以相信什么
What's hard to believe?
你们俩啊
Well y'know, I mean it's you guys.
你们老干这种事情
You do this kind of stuff, you know?
你们在赌城说要结婚又不结了
I mean, You were gonna get married in Vegas,  and then you backed out.
我并不认为你们会真的同居
I guess I'm not upset
对不起
because I don't see you guys going through with it. I'm sorry.
瑞秋
Rachel.
事情已经确定了
lt's going to happen.
钱德勒会搬进来
Chandler will move in here.
-但是...  -你先听我说完
- But l- -  - l know, just let me finish, okay?
这不是在赌城时的
This isn't something that we just...
一时冲动
just impulsively decided to do in Vegas.
我们真的想要住在一起
This is something that we both really want.
我们会住在一起
And it is going to happen.
是吗
lt is?
真的吗
Really?
没错
Yeah, sweetie.
我们不能再住在一起了吗
You mean, we're not gonna live together anymore?
不能
No.
天啊  我会好想你
Oh, my God. l'm gonna miss you so much.
我也是
l'm gonna miss you.
这是一个时代的结束
l mean, it's the end of an era!
我知道
l know!
-再见  -又来了
- Okay, bye.  - Oh, no.
你去办注销了吗
So did you get the annulment?
-我办不了  -我就知道  因为你爱瑞秋
- l couldn't.  - l knew it. Because you love Rachel.
不是那样的  事情比想像中复杂...
lt's not that. Okay? Annulments are more complicated- -
爱让它变得复杂
Complicated because of the love.
我不爱瑞秋
l do not love Rachel.
我现在就去告诉她
I'm gonna tell her right now about the whole thing
好尽快把手续办好
so we can get this marriage annulled as fast as possible. Okay?
我如果爱她会这么做吗
Would l do that if l loved her?
我现在更确信你爱她了
l've never been more convinced of your love for her.
我对瑞秋没有感觉  好吗
l do not have feelings for Rachel, okay?
怎么啦
Oh, what's wrong?
莫妮卡和钱德勒真的要同居了
Monica and Chandler are really moving in here
我得搬出去  一切都要变了
...and l have to move out  and everything is changing.
过来  别难过  不会有事的
Oh, my God, come here, come here.  lt's okay.
都会好起来的
Everything's gonna be okay.
-谢谢你  -不客气
- Thank you.  - Of course.
罗斯和瑞秋结婚了
So Ross and Rachel got married.
莫妮卡和钱德勒差点结婚
Monica and Chandler  almost got married.
我们该不该搞在一起呢
You think we should hook up?
要
Oh, we do.
但不是现在
But not just yet.
是吗  那是什么时候
Really? Well, when?
好吧
Okay.
好  首先钱德勒和莫妮卡会结婚
Well, first Chandler and Monica  will get married...
还会发大财
...and be filthy rich, by the way.
但婚姻会破裂
But it won't work out.
-天哪  -是啊
- Wow.  - l know.
然后我会为钱嫁给钱德勒
Then l'll marry Chandler  for the money.
你会娶瑞秋生几个漂亮小孩
And you'll marry Rachel  and have the beautiful kids.
太好了
Great.
接着我们就抛弃他们结婚
But then we ditch those two and we get married.
我们会有钱德勒的财产  瑞秋的孩子
We'll have Chandler's money and Rachel's kids.
监护权很好抢
Getting custody will be easy
因为瑞秋酗酒
because of Rachel's drinking problem.
那罗斯呢
What about Ross?
我不想说太多
l don't want to go into the whole thing.
不过我们吵架  我杀了他
But we have words and l kill him.